

INFO

NAME Reuben Marland

PHONE +44 7552 735 780

reubenuk@hotmail.co.uk

www.linkedin.com/in/reuben-marland

ADDRESS
BS65DW - Bristol

WORK EXPERIENCE

BARTENDER 2019-2020 The Mason Arms - Oxford

FARMER 2020-2021 Rectory Farm - Oxford

CHEF 2021-present
Bambalan - Line - Bristol
The Downs Cafe - Solo-Line Bristol
The Metropolitan - Line - Bristol

ACHIEVEMENTS

Top 50 UK out of 80,000 for computational thinking

STUDENT MATHEMATICS

AMBASSADOR

University of Warwick 1st year

- selected from 350 peers

REUBEN MARIAND

MECHANICAL ENGINEER

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Over the past four years, I've dedicated myself to numerous projects, taking on diverse roles that showcased my strong work ethic, passion for engineering, and sociability. My self-taught knowledge in software has positioned me to lead initiatives in 3D modeling, coding, and graphic design.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Design of a 2DoF robotic arm, design of a manufacturing system for a door dampner led entrepreneurship team
 - University of Bristol / 4th year team projects / Ongoing
 - Lead robotic arm design within fusion alongside integrated API outputs
 - Innovated feedback control simulations within matlab providing data for backlash
 - Directed KPI analysis \pm simulation of production in SIMIO Solution Software
 - Coordinating a team of 4 in the conceptualisation of an waste reducing mobile app, developing through market research and leading pitch presentation.
- DESIGN OF A COST-EFFECTIVE SOLAR POWERED E-READER
 University of Bristol / 3rd year solo project / 68%
 - Focus on extensive research, project planning, MATLAB coding for a component choice algorithm, PCB design using EagleCAD, Python programming the onboard Raspberry Pi Pico.
 - Project tailored towards algorithmic manufacturing solutions alongside electronical and computer science research.
- DESIGN OF A CONVERTIBLE CAR ROOF

Univeristy of Bristol / 2nd year team project / 70%

- Led the design of the Fusion 360 CAD modelling, including joint setuo allocations for a comprehensive FEA analysis.
- Played a pivotal role in concept selection, initial designs and technical drawings.

EDUCATION

MEng Integrated Masters in Mechanical Engineering
University of Bristol / 2020 - present

Tailored towards control, manufacturing and innovation.

Achieved 68% in 3rd year. Persuing a first with full intent.

A-Levels
d'Overbroecks / 2017-2019

Mathematics - A*

Further Mathematics - A*

Physics - A*

SKILLS

RELEVENT MODULES

FUSION 360	MATLAB	Y3 - INDIVIDUAL RESEARCH PROJECT (68)
INVENTOR	PYTHON	Y2 - ENGINEERING PRACTICE (70)
NASTRAN	PHOTOSHOP	Y3 - DYNAMICS AND CONTROL (79)
EAGLECAD	ARDUINO	Y3 - ENGINEERING MANAGEMENT (68)
FULL DRIVING LICENCE		Y2 - MATERIALS (76)